Guide to the Houston Women's Caucus for Art Records
University of Houston Libraries
- Photographs
  - Prints
    - Member Show Catalog - Sharon Stewart (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Member Show Catalog - Richard Stout (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Member Show Catalog - Lin Swannet (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Member Show Catalog - Marasu Takiguchi (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Member Show Catalog - Toby Topek (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Member Show Catalog - Josefa Vaughn (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Member Show Catalog - Casey Williams (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Member Show Catalog - Frank Williams (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Member Show Catalog - Geoff Winningham (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Member Show Catalog - Unidentified Artists (b/w), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - "Self-Images" artwork (b/w), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - “Private Rites” artwork - Susie Rosmarin (b/w), January 22-February 23, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - “Private Rites” artwork - Kelly Alison (b/w), January 22-February 23, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - “Private Rites” artwork - Unidentified Artist (b/w), January 22-February 23, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - Artwork - Janet Zweig (b/w), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - "Contemporary Women in Documentary Photography" artwork - Annie Liebowitz (b/w), March 1-24, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - "Contemporary Women in Documentary Photography" artwork - Ruth Pine Morgan (b/w), March 1-24, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - "Contemporary Women in Documentary Photography" artwork - Wendy Watriss (b/w), March 1-24, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - “Contemporary Women in Documentary Photography” artwork - Miscellaneous (b/w), March 1-24, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - National WCA Conference Houston, TX (b/w), 1988 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - "Women Taking a Stand" panel (color), August 1992 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - "From Within Walls" artwork Molly Campbell (b/w), November 14, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - "Untold Stories" reception Diana Block, juror (color), November 12-December 31, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Studio Tour (color), approximately 1993 (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - "Women and the Representation of Aging" - Gay Block (color), March 12- April 19, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - "Women and the Representation of Aging" - Elise Mitchell Sanford (b/w), March 12-April 19, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - "Women and the Representation of Aging" - Miscellaneous (b/w), March 12-April 19, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - "Handmade Book" workshop (b/w), April 1994 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - "Handmade Book" workshop (color), April 1994 (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Postcard Show artwork (b/w), May 1994 (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - Postcard Show opening (color), May 1994 (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - "Social Reflections" artwork Elisa Alvarado (b/w), July 24-August 27, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - "Social Reflections" opening Elisa Alvarado (color), July 24-August 27, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - "Out of the Sky" artwork - Anne Noggle (b/w), [c. 1990] (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - "Living With AIDS" panel (color), 1994 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - "A Conversation Piece" (b/w), January 4-February 10, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - "Companeras" opening (b/w), February 12-March 31, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - "Companeras" opening (color), February 12-March 31, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - "Healing Works" artwork (color), April 11-May 21, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - "Healing Works" artwork (b/w), April 11-May 21, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Michea Performance (color), June 1995 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - "Creative Communities, Making Friends" opening (color), September 23-November 3, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - "Out of the Cold" artwork (color), September 30-October 29, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - "Serial Imagery" artwork (color), November 11-25, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - "Aubrey McCaskell's Place" opening (color), December 1995-February 1996 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - "4×4" Fundraiser (color), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" (b/w), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 94-95)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" artwork - Louise DeMore (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" artwork - B.R. Gates (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" artwork - Catherine Gill (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" artwork - Karen Hubutzel (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows:" artwork - DeAnne Lemley (color), January 5-February 25, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - "1/2 of 1/2 of 1/2" - Matuschka (b/w), March 1-April 22, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - "1/2 of 1/2 of 1/2" - Matuschka (color), March 1-April 22, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 102-103)
    - "Salon Des Oeuvres Refuses" artwork (color), May 4-June 2, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - "Drop In, Switch On" (color), December 7, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - "Drop In, Switch On" (b/w), December 7, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - "Visions: The Women's Expo" booth (b/w), 1996 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - "Chapel of Pioneers" artwork (color), 1996 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - “Banners Project” - International Quilt Festival (color), 1996, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - "Banners Project" - Artifacts Gallery at Champion Village (color), approximately 1997 (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - "Banners Project" - Fashion Group International (color), 1998 (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - "Banners Project" - Miscellaneous (color), 1998 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - "Mother Earth" ground breaking, September 1997 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - “Mother Earth” planning, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - “Slip and Slide Program” (color), January 13, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - “Limp” (color), May 6-June 10, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - Art Guys Striptease (color), approximatley 1996 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Artwork - Nancy Haglund, undated (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Unidentified Show - Steve Hoover (b/w), approximately 1984 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Catbox (band) (b/w; color), undated (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Firehouse exterior (color), approximately 1995 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - HWCA Board (color), approximately 1995 (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - HWCA Members (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - HWCA President - Joy Mullett (color), approximately 1997 (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - Members - Gertrude Barnstone (color), undated (Box 12, Folder 125)
    - Members - Lin Swanner (color), undated (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Members - Lin Swanner (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - Members - Unidentified Member (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - Printmaking show artwork (color), approximately 1996 (Box 12, Folder 129)
    - "Recycle Sculpture" artwork (color), approximately 1996 (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Renovation (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Unidentified Artwork (color), approximately 1984 (Box 12, Folder 132)
    - Unidentified Artwork (color), approximately 1994 (Box 12, Folder 133)
    - Unidentified Event (b/w), approximately 1995 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Unidentified Event (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Unidentified Event (color), approximately 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - Unidentified Events (color), undated (Box 12, Folder 137-138)
    - Unidentified Panels (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Unidentified Show (color) (3 items), approximately 1995 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Unidentified Show (color) (7 items), approximately 1995 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Unidentified Show (b/w) (16 items), approximately 1985 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Unidentified Shows (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 143-148)
      Folder 143 contains 4 items; Folder 144 contains 4 items; Folder 145 contains 1 item; Folder 146 contains 4 items; Folder 147 contains 1 item; Folder 148 contains 1 item
    - Unidentified Workshop (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - Miscellaneous (b/w), undated (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - Miscellaneous (color), undated (Box 12, Folder 151)
    - Block Printing Workshop, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Catalogue, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Various, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
- Clippings
  The Clippings series includes all newspaper and magazine clippings found throughout the original arrangement of the HWCA papers. Due to the great number and concern for preservation of these clippings, they were separated into their own series and copied onto acid-free paper when possible. Some clippings were too large to copy and have been removed into Box 14, although they remain in the Clippings series. The folders are arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically. They predominantly follow a similar pattern as the series for the collection.
  - AIDS Stories, 1995, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Art Spaces - Contemporary Arts Museum, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Art Spaces - Courthouse Annex, June 1995-February 1996 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Art Spaces - Intercontinental Airport, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Art Spaces - Lawndale Art Center, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Art Spaces - Menil Collection, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Art Spaces - Museum of Fine Arts, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Art Spaces - Rothko Chapel, 1961-1970 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Artists, 1971, 1980-1995 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Art News, 1980-1995 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Conferences - National WCA Conference - New Orleans, LA, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Conferences - National WCA Conference, Houston, TX, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - "Visions: The Women's Expo", March 18-19, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Events - Artist in Society, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Events - Studio Tours, approximately 1980 (Box 12, Folder 166)
  - Finances - Cultural Arts Council of Houston, approximately 1986 (Box 12, Folder 167)
  - Finances - “4x4 Recreational Vehicle", October 8, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 168)
  - Finances - "Drop In, Switch On", 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 169)
  - Finances - Miscellaneous, 1980-1995 (Box 12, Folder 170)
  - Firehouse, 1982-1983, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - Helen Orman, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 172)
  - Houston Image, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 173)
  - NEA Battles Censorship, 1989-1995 (Box 12, Folder 174)
  - Shows - "AH-HA", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 175)
  - Shows - Member Shows, 1983-1985 (Box 12, Folder 176)
  - Shows - “Creatures", December 1985-January 1986 (Box 12, Folder 177)
  - Shows - "Women in Photography", 1986 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - Shows - Gorilla Girls, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - Shows - Finley, Karen, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - Shows - "Boxworks", May 1991 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - Shows - "Women Taking a Stand", September 1992 (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Shows - “Wild Women Art Savage", September-October, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Shows - "Perceptions of Men", 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - Shows - “Women and Aging", March – April, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 185)
  - Shows - “Out of the Sky", November-December, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Shows - “A Conversational Piece", January-February, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Shows - “Compañeras", February-March, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - Shows - “Out of the Cold", September-October, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 189)
  - Shows - “Banners Project", 1996 (Box 12, Folder 190)
  - Shows - "McCaskell's Place" - Aubrey McCaskell, December 18, 1995-February 1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Shows - "Why Girls Can't Paint Cows" Artgirls of the West, February 1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Shows - "1/2 of 1/2 of 1/2" - Matuschka, March 1-April 22, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Shows - "Salon des Oeuvres Refuses", May 1996 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Shows - "Altars as Art", October 1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Shows - "Luscious Show", January 1997 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Shows - Canary Project, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Shows - “Is this a joke or what?”, March 1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Shows - “Limp", May 6-June 10, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Shows - Miscellaneous, 1983-1996 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Women's Issues, 1980-1997 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - National WCA Conference - Houston, TX, 1988 (Ovs box 14, Folder 5)
  - NEA Battles Censorship, 1989 (Ovs box 14, Folder 6)
  - Houston Foto Fest, 1986 (Ovs box 14, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971, 1980-1988, 1995-1996 (Ovs box 14, Folder 8)
  - 6 Artists/ 6 Idioms, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Chaja Verveer, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Contemporary Arts Museum Benefit, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - The Famine Within, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Gorilla Girls, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - In Art, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - “Women and the Arts”, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Women Recognition, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 41)
- General Visual Arts (GVA), 1979-2002
  This series contains general information related to the visual arts in Houston, little of it directly related to HWCA. The series contains material from the years 1979-2002, including some with no date. One folder is located in oversized Box 14. There are six sub-series, arranged alphabetically: Artists, Art Spaces, Journals, Organizations, Politics, Miscellaneous. The Artists sub-series contains an alphabetical arrangement of resumes and biographies of various artists, predominantly from the Houston area and involved with the HWCA. The Art Spaces sub-series includes information about various galleries and museums in Houston. The Firehouse, the HWCA gallery, is excluded from this sub-series because it merits a series of its own. The Journals sub-series contains various arts journals. The Organizations sub-series contains fliers, brochures, and other information about different artists’ groups or organizations supporting the arts. The Politics sub-series includes information on different political issues and candidates involving women and the arts. The Miscellaneous sub-series contains general information that did not easily fall into other categories within this series. Most of the documents in this series are related to local issues. Some organizations and political issues, however, include information from the state and national level.
  - Artists
    - A-H, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - J-Z, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Art Spaces
    - Courthouse Annex, September 1995-Spring 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Contemporary Arts Museum, 1986, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Intercontinental Airport, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Lawndale Art Center, 1983, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - O’Kane Gallery, 1997, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - The Orange Show, 1979, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Rothko Chapel, February 1971 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1981-1998 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Journals
    - 1985-1997 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - 1980-1996 (Ovs box 14, Folder 9)
  - Organizations
    - Business Volunteers for the Arts, 1987, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Coalition of Women's Arts Organizations, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Community Artists' Collective, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Cultural Arts Council of Houston, 1980-1989 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Cultural Arts Council of Houston, 1990-1997 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Cultural Arts Council of Houston, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Gorilla Girls, 1987-1992 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Houston Center for Photography, 1984, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Houston Coalition for the Visual Arts, 1990, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Houston/Harris County Task Force, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - International Art Exchange, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1989, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Texas Accountants and Lawyers for the Arts, 1982-1996 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Texas Accountants and Lawyers for the Arts, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts, 1980-1994 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Women and Their Work Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Women in the Visual and Literary Arts, 1994-2000 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Women’s Resource Directory, 1996-2000 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1986-1998 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Politics
    - Citizens Environmental Coalition, 1999-2002 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Federal Art Bank, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Houston, 1980-1996 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Presidential Election, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Women and Art, approximately 1990 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Constituents, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Opportunities for Artists, 1993-2001 (Box 13, Folder 49)
- Posters
  The Posters series contains all oversized posters for various shows and conferences. The fourteen posters that fall into this series are arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
  - National WCA Conferences, 1979-1988 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10)
    - Washington, D.C., January 30-February 3, 1979 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10, Item 1)
    - “Women of Art: Connections West,” San Francisco, CA, February 24-26, 1981 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10, Item 2)
    - "Dedication '83: Philadelphia/Houston," Philadelphia, PA, January 14-April 9, 1983 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10, Item 3)
    - "Women: The Power of Art," Philadelphia, PA, February 15-18, 1983 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10, Item 4)
    - Conference Highlights, Houston, TX, February 1988 (Ovs box 14, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - Shows, 1984-1996 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11)
    - "1984 Show", March 6-24, 1984 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 1)
    - "Self-Images: the 1985 Show", April 4-May 10, 1985 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 2)
    - "Take an Alternate Route", approximately 1986 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 3)
    - Dorothy Hood/Jeanne Norsworthy Cocktail Reception, February 2, 1988 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 4)
    - "Karen Finley in Performance", October 27-28, 1989 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 5)
    - "Companeras" (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 6)
    - "Time for Prevention" - Matuschka, 1996 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 7)
    - "Life" - Matuschka, 1996 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 8)
    - “Carving the Forces of Change: Celebrating Women in the Arts”, February 7-12, 1997 (Ovs box 14, Folder 11, Item 9)
  - Council for Visual and Performing Arts Calendar, 1991-1992 (Ovs box 14, Folder 12)
- Lectures, Papers and Speeches
  This series contains lectures, papers and speeches that pertain to women’s issues, art, and women in art. Most of the material contained in this series does not pertain to HWCA, though lectures given at HWCA conferences are also included.
  - “An Open Letter to the Board of Trustees of the Museum of the Fine Arts Houston", 1981 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - “The Business of Art,” by Ann Webb, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - “The Debate of ‘Essentialism’” by Karen A. Bearor, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Eleanora Anitova, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - “Facing Each Other” by Trinh T. Minh Ha, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - “The Feisty Woman’s Plan-Ahead Guide”, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - “The Needle and the Eye” by Joyce Fernandez, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - “Notes From an Old-Fashioned Feminist” by Lucy Lippard, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - “Packaging the ‘Trail of Tears’” by Susan A. Miller, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - “Parenthood and the Creative Process” by Joan Semnel, undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - “Social Criticism Without Philosophy” by Nancy Fraser and Linda J. Nicholson, undated (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - “What is a Millennium Artist?” by John Worldpeace, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - “Woman as Bearer of Meaning, Not Maker of Meaning”, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - “Women of Power: Balancing Art-Making & Motherhood” by Charleen Touchette, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 55)
- Printed Materials
  This series contains publications and printed materials by both the WCA and other organizations. The majority of the material contained in this series deals with the art community.
  - Artist’s Checklist, undated (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Art Papers, May/June 1988 (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Center, July/August 1992 (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Intertribal Council of Houston Newsletter, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - “Manual of Speakers, Artists and Research Areas”, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Various, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - “WCA Chapter Representatives”, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - “WCA Workbook ‘Estate Planning For Artists’”, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - “WCA Handbook ‘Presenting Your Work’”, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - Women Artist News, Summer 1988 (Box 15, Folder 65)